## **GEORGE TSIMIS**

## Software Engineer

📞 (347) 739-6542 🔞 gt2186@gmail.com 🕜 www.georgetsimis.com

New York, NY

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Software Engineer

08/2022 - Present

## **Aspen Capital**

New York, NY

 Project lead to greatly enhance, and currently maintain, the automated phone system (Twilio API), including testing / error logging, allowing for making payments, saving bank accounts, and configuring autopay. Monthly payments processed / revenue collected through phone system averages 3K+ / \$5M+

- Project lead for migrating nightly process that updates databases with payment information, from Chase, to AWS utilizing S3, Lambdas, SQS, and SNS. Replaced previous process of stored long SQL procedures resulting in better logging, error handling, and process efficiency
- Maintain / add features to user-facing app, which borrowers (19K+ active with growing adoption) use to make payments, configure autopay, upload / download documents, view loan information / payment history. Monthly payments processed / revenue collected through user-facing app averages 11K+ / \$20M+
- Developed and maintain, including writing tests, the API and micro-services written in Java / Spring Boot and Node.js. Add RESTful endpoints that return appropriate data to frontend. Participate in rotational weekly on-call for micro-services. Proficient in IntelliJ IDEA
- Added backend feature, utilizing Intercom API & AWS SNS, that sends two email reminders
  to borrowers that started the process, in user-facing app, of manually linking their bank
  accounts through micro-deposits, to complete the process
- Added feature that allows admins to configure autopay on behalf of borrowers, in internal app, for loans with various statuses (i.e. current, bankruptcy, commercial), requiring different input parameters and backend logic depending on loan status
- Collaborate with teams across the business to understand needs, improve processes, and create realistic plans to complete goals. Participate in software design and architecture discussions. Review team members' pull requests and provide feedback to improve codebase quality

## Software Engineer I

02/2022 - 07/2022

## LynxDx, Inc.

Ann Arbor, MI (Remote)

- Helped rebuild the Laboratory Information Management System in 3 months from the ground up, resulting in improved performance, scalability, and user experience
- Redesigned all database tables and set up new associations for increased efficiency and performance of database querying
- Added backend and frontend tests allowing the team to confirm new code hasn't affected previous working code

## Financial Data Analyst

07/2018 - 07/2021

## **Moody's Corporation**

New York, NY

- Ensured accuracy, consistency, and analytical value of a portfolio of 300+ public and private business entities
- Liaised with senior analysts to resolve queries about financial data used in the ratings process
- Managed and supported an offshore team, that performed data entry, by analyzing their work, making corrections, and providing feedback
- Trained new hires on portfolio management, accounting standards used in the ratings process, and Moody's based software

#### Mathematics Adjunct Lecturer

08/2016 - 12/2017

## City University of New York

New York, NY

- Taught undergraduate courses (approx. 35 students) in elementary algebra, college algebra & trigonometry, precalculus, and calculus
- Created course syllabi and lectures in alignment with CUNY standards to ensure students perform their best on departmental exams
- Designed homework problems of varying difficulty to reinforce concepts learned in class
- Held office hours to address students' concerns and develop study action plans to facilitate a better understanding of difficult concepts



## **SUMMARY**

Software Engineer with 2+ years of professional full stack experience. Previous experience in finance at Moody's Corporation assisting lead analysts in the ratings process, and as a Mathematics Adjunct Lecturer at the City University of New York.

#### **SKILLS**

AWS · Axios · CSS3 · Docker · Draw.io ·

Figma · Git · GitHub · GraphQL · HTML5 ·

Intercom · Java · JavaScript · Jest · Jira ·

Kubernetes · Mantine · MongoDB · Next.js ·

Node.js · Plaid · PostgreSQL · Pulumi ·

Python · React.js · React Testing Library ·

Ruby on Rails · Spring Framework · SQL ·

Tailwind CSS · Twilio · TypeScript

## **EDUCATION**

# App Academy

11/2021

Web development bootcamp with 1000-hour curriculum and < 3% acceptance rate

# CUNY Queens College

09/2021

Master of Arts in Mathematics

## **CUNY Queens College**

09/2019

Bachelor of Arts in Accounting Minor in Economics

## **CUNY Queens College**

06/2016

Bachelor of Arts in Mathematics (Honors)